Guide to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Audio Collection ALBA.AUDIO.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Audio Collection
1964-2002
ALBA.AUDIO.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
3.0 linear feet (175 audiocassettes)
U.S. men and woman who had volunteered for service in the Spanish Civil War joined together as the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) in December 1937 upon their return from Spain. In the 1970s the organization began to collect historical materials from its members, with a view to creating an archive documenting its history. This general audiotape collection is made up of tapes gathered by VALB over many years. Some items were donated by veterans and their families or by individuals who created them in the course of various projects (conferences, rallies, radio programs, etc.). The collection includes many interviews with individual veterans, tapes of public events, and a series of music tapes.
Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Other ALBA collections at the Tamiment Library, NYU.
Provenance
This collection came to the Tamiment Library as part of the original accession of material from the ALBA Archives in 2001.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of 175 audio cassettes collected by or related to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB). The audio collection was formed from tapes gathered by VALB over many years. Some items were donated by veterans and their families or by individuals who created them in the course of various projects.
The items cover a wide array of materials including: interviews with individual veterans, live (amateur) recordings of events in Spain, musical recordings (both personal and commercial), and recordings of VALB events such as the 50th anniversary celebrations in the Bay Area and NYC. The interviews' focus is usually on the veterans' memories of their time in Spain.
The tapes are arranged in three series. Series I: Interviews, 1964-2002; includes interviews with individuals and with small groups and talks presented, for example, in classes; it also includes publicly aired interviews from radio programs. Series II: Public Events, 1970-1999; includes presentations by veterans on trips to Nicaragua and China, live recordings from the veterans' trip to Spain in 1986, and the 50th anniversary celebrations in the Bay area and NYC. Series III: Music, 1976-2002; includes both commercial releases and home recordings by veterans and others. Some of the recordings are tape copies of other recordings, primarily records. Notable is a well executed home recording by Max Parker, of his memories of being a prisoner of war in Spain, which combines narration with song -- possibly a preliminary recording for or an unedited version of material he eventually released on a commercial recording.
Historical/Biographical Note
U.S. men and women who had volunteered for service in the Spanish Civil War joined together as the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) in December 1937 as they began to return from Spain.
The organization adopted a constitution and a formal structure in 1939. VALB originally raised money for the embattled Spanish Republic, assisted wounded veterans, helped veterans resettle and find jobs, and tried to awaken the U.S. public to the significance of the Spanish Civil War and the Loyalist cause. In later years, VALB campaigned strenuously against the Franco regime in Spain, assisted refugees and addressed other political issues, including U.S. policy in Cuba, Nicaragua and Vietnam. In addition to their headquarters in New York City, VALB had "posts" Los Angeles, San Francisco, and Chicago, and more informal groups in other cities and regions.
In the 1970s the organization began to collect historical materials from its members, with a view to creating an archive documenting its history. That archive, originally housed at Brandeis University, is now part of the Tamiment Library at New York University.
For additional information on the history of VALB see the guide to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Records, ALBA #19.
Arrangement
The tapes are organized in 3 series: I: Interviews, Speeches, Discussions, 1964-2002; II: Public events, 1970-1999; III: Music, 1976-2002.
Each recording has been assigned a unique item number (e.g. ALBA A 1-001), and the collection is arranged in item number order. For interview tapes (Series I) the item number order roughly follows the alphabetical order of the last name of the interviewee, with a few exceptions. Some tapes contain multiple interviewees and are ordered according to how the names were written on the cassette. Tapes in Series II and III are arranged alphabetically by title.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Researcher is responsible for the cost of creating an access copy of any item.
For details E-mail: gail.malmgreen@nyu.edu
Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Abraham Lincoln Battalion.; Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Brigada Internacional, XV.; Audiocassettes.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |v Biography.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |v Personal narratives, American.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |v Songs and music.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Participation, American |v Interviews.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Veterans.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939.
- Series I: Interviews, Speeches, Discussions, 1964-2002.
  - Alvarez del Vayo, Julio (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-001)
  - Bailey, Bill (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-002)
  - Balchowsky, Edward R. (Interview in Spain by Blythe Allison Bennett), Oct 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-003)
  - Balchowsky, Edward R.; Milton Wolff; Louis (Lou) Gordon (Interview in Spain by Blythe Allison Bennett), Oct 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-004)
  - Beebe, Vernold (Interview), Jul 29, 1970 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-005)
  - Bessie, Alvah Cecil (Interview) [tape 2 of 4], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-006)
  - Bessie, Alvah Cecil (Interview) [tape 3 of 4], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-007)
  - Bessie, Alvah Cecil (Interview) [tape 4 of 4], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-008)
  - Birnbaum, Saul; Harry Fisher; Robert Gladnick (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-009)
  - Birnbaum, Saul; Harry Fisher; Robert Gladnick (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-010)
  - Boudin, Leonard (at the University of Colorado speaking on the U. S., Nicaragua and the World Court) [Master], Mar 19, 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-011)
  - Boudin, Leonard (at the University of Colorado speaking on the U. S., Nicaragua and the World Court) [Copy], Mar 19, 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-012)
  - Brier, Morris (BROKEN) [tape 1 of 2], Sep 2, 1981 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-013)
  - Brier, Morris (Interview) [tape 2 of 2], Sep 2, 1981 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-014)
  - Brown, Archie (Interview), May 10, 1988 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-015)
  - Cogswell, Theodore Rose; Arthur Harold Landis (Letter from Cogswell to Landis), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-016)
  - Collins, Joe; George Henry Leiviska (Interview), Sep 1968 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-017)
  - Dent, Wally; Lionel Edwards; Fred Mattis Corter (Interview on Canadian Radio Program "As It Happens")[Master], Feb 16, 1981 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-018)
  - Dent, Wally; Lionel Edwards; Fred Mattis Corter (Interview on Canadian Radio Program "As It Happens")[Copy], Feb 16, 1981 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-019)
  - Fisher, Harry (Interview on WNYC), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-020)
  - Fishman, Moe (Moses); Harry Fisher; William Cane Van Felix (Interview on CWA Local 80 Radio Program, ? "Communique"), Aug 4, 1987 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-021)
  - Friedman, Maurice Wolf (Interview with sister Muriel Eldrige, and husband Richard Eldrige), 1988 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-022)
  - Gandall, William (Question and Answer), May 10, 1988 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-023)
  - Garlin, Sender (Interview on KGNU Radio, Boulder, CO), Feb 25, 1985 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-024)
  - Garlin, Sender (Party in His Honor), March 1, 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-025)
  - Garlin, Sender (Public Speaking, University of Colorado)[tape 2], Dec 1, 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-026)
  - Garlin, Sender (Questions and Answers at University of Colorado), Oct 3, 1989 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-027)
  - Gates, John (Interview) [tape 1 of 4], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-028)
  - Gates, John (Interview) [tape 2 of 4], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-029)
  - Gates, John (Interview) [tape 3 of 4], May 14, 1970 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-030)
  - Gates, John (Interview) [tape 4 of 4], May 14, 1970 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-031)
  - Gates, John (Memorial Meeting), Jun 19, 1992 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-032)
  - Gates, John (Memorial), Sep 10, 1992 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-033)
  - Gibbs, Theodore (Interview with Daughter, Michelle Gibbs re: Her Father), 1977 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-034)
  - Giler, Henry (Public Speaking), Jan 4, 1974 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-035)
  - Gladnick, Robert (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-036)
  - Gladnick, Robert (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-037)
  - Gladnick, Robert (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-038)
  - Gladnick, Robert (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-039)
  - Gladnick, Robert (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-040)
  - Gladnick, Robert (BROKEN), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-041)
  - Gladnick, Robert (BROKEN), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-042)
  - Gladnick, Robert (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-043)
  - Gladnick, Robert (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-044)
  - Gladnick, Robert (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-045)
  - Gladnick, Robert (Interview), May 19, 1970 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-046)
  - Goldring, Benjamin (Asking Question of Roy Cohn; audio recording of a TV show), Jul 20, 1980 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-047)
  - Hakam, Harry; Milton Wolff (Interview in Spain by Blythe Allison Bennett), Oct 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-048)
  - Harriman, Emanuel (Manny); Donald Blair Macleod; Sidney Levine; George Foucek; Arthur Harold Landis (Interview), Oct 18, 1964 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-049)
  - Hollander, Herman (Interview), Jun 15, 1970 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-050)
  - Hollander, Herman (BROKEN), Jun 15, 1970 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-051)
  - Hollander, Herman (Interview), Jan 10, 1980 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-052)
  - Hollander, Herman (Interview), Jan 10, 1980 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-053)
  - Iceland, Benjamin Isaac (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-054)
  - Jones, James Moore (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-055)
  - Kailin, Clarence; Edie Newman; Milton Felson (Interview on WORT-FM) [Master], Dec 19, 1996 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-056)
  - Kailin, Clarence; Edie Newman; Milton Felson (Interview) [Copy], Dec 19, 1996 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-057)
  - Kobeluch, John (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-058)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold (Discussing his Cancer and Interviewing his Doctor for Article), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-059)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-060)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-061)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-062)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold (Notes for future writing), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-063)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold (Outlining a Story), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-064)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold; Donald Blair MacLeod (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-065)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold; Donald Blair MacLeod (Letter from Landis to Macleod), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-066)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold; Evelyn Hutchins; Carl Frederick Geiser (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-067)
  - Landis, Arthur Harold; Steve Nelson (Interview), 1978 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-068)
  - Lanser, Manny (Morris) (Interview) [tape 1 of 2], Mar 8, 1997 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-069)
  - Lanser, Manny (Morris) (Interview) [tape 2 of 2], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-070)
  - Levenson, Leonard Bertram; Samuel Gonshak; Charles Nusser (Interview in Spain by Blythe Allison Bennett), Oct 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-071)
  - Levine, Sidney (Interview and songs recorded from a record), Sep 21, 1977 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-072)
  - Levine, Sidney (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-073)
  - Levine, Sidney (Interview), Sep 23, 1977 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-074)
  - Levine, Sidney (Recorded at a Birthday Party), Apr 29, 1977 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-075)
  - Mattersdorfer, Fred; Wally Dent; Lionel Edwards (Interview on "As It Happens" with Alan Maitland, Toronto, Canada), Feb 16, 1981 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-076)
  - Matthews, William (aka Matvenko) (Interview) [tape 1 of 2], Jun 21, 1980 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-077)
  - Matthews, William (aka Matvenko) (Interview) [tape 2 of 2], Jun 21, 1980 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-078)
  - Nelson, Steve (Interview) [tape 1 of 3], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-079)
  - Nelson, Steve (Interview) [tape 2 of 3], Feb 21, 1970 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-080)
  - Nelson, Steve (Interview) [tape 3 of 3], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-081)
  - Nelson, Steve (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-082)
  - Nelson, Steve (Interview), 1978 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-083)
  - Nusser, Charles (Interview with Judith Montell on WGBH, Boston), Nov 12, 1992 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-084)
  - Nusser, Charles (Interview), Jul 18, 1970 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-085)
  - Nusser, Charles (Interview), Jun 18, 1970 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-086)
  - Nusser, Charles (Interview), Nov 12, 1991 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-087)
  - Nusser, Charles; Harry Fisher, Vaughn Love (Discussing Oliver Law on WNYC radio), Feb 8, 1989 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-088)
  - Nusser, Charles; Harry Fisher, Vaughn Love (Discussing Oliver Law on WNYC radio), 1989 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-089)
  - Parker, Max (Narration of experiences in Spain and songs)[related to "Al Tocar Diana"], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-090)
  - Parker, Max; Milton Wolff; Manny (Morris) Lanser (Interview in Spain by Blythe Allison Bennett), Oct 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-091)
  - Peck, Samuel (Interview) [tape 1 of 2], Jan 19, 1980 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-092)
  - Peck, Samuel (Interview) [tape 2 of 2], Jan 19, 1980 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-093)
  - Randall, Jr., Harry Wayland (Interview with Erika Gottfried) [tape 1 of 2] [Master], Apr 10, 2002 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-094)
  - Randall, Jr., Harry Wayland (Interview with Erika Gottfried) [tape 2 of 2] [Master], Apr 10, 2002 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-095)
  - Randall, Jr., Harry Wayland (Interview with Erika Gottfried) [tape 1 of 2] [Copy], Apr 10, 2002 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-096)
  - Randall, Jr., Harry Wayland (Interview with Erika Gottfried) [tape 2 of 2] [Copy], Apr 10, 2002 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-097)
  - Randall, Jr., Harry Wayland (Interview with Erika Gottfried) [Master], Sep 12, 2002 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-098)
  - Randall, Jr., Harry Wayland (Interview with Erika Gottfried) [Copy], Sep 12, 2002 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-099)
  - Rody, John (Interview) [tape 1 of 3], Jul 7, 1980 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-100)
  - Rody, John (Interview) [tape 2 of 3], Jul 7, 1980 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-101)
  - Rody, John (Interview) [tape 3 of 3], Jul 8, 1980 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-102)
  - Sennett, William; Donald Blair MacLeod (Interview), Aug 1981 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-103)
  - Stamm, Morris (Public Speaking on trip to Spain; Recorded by David M. Miller) [tape 1 of 2], Nov 11, 1977 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-104)
  - Stamm, Morris (Public Speaking on trip to Spain; Recorded by David M. Miller) [tape 2 of 2], Nov 11, 1977 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-105)
  - Steck, Robert (Interview by Byron T. Wells) [tape 1 of 7], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-106)
  - Steck, Robert (Interview by Byron T. Wells) [tape 2 of 7], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-107)
  - Steck, Robert (Interview by Byron T. Wells) [tape 3 of 7], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-108)
  - Steck, Robert (Interview by Byron T. Wells) [tape 4 of 7], Jul 25, 1999 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-109)
  - Steck, Robert (Interview by Byron T. Wells) [tape 5 of 7], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-110)
  - Steck, Robert (Interview by Byron T. Wells) [tape 6 of 7], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-111)
  - Steck, Robert (Interview by Byron T. Wells) [tape 7 of 7], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-112)
  - Taylor, Robert Munson (Interview) [tape 1 of 2], Jun 27, 1980 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-113)
  - Taylor, Robert Munson (Interview) [tape 2 of 2], Jun 27, 1980 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-114)
  - Toney, Anthony; Al Warren; Ralph Fasanella (Interview), Oct 27, 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-115)
  - Unidentified (Interview on lessons to be learned from SCW), 1982 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-116)
  - Unidentified Veterans (Interview and speaking amongst themselves at a meeting), Dec 6, 1970 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-117)
  - Unidentified Veterans (Interview and speaking amongst themselves at a meeting), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-118)
  - Unidentified Veterans (Interview for British Documentary), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-119)
  - Unidentified Veterans (Interview) [tape 1 of 2], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-120)
  - Unidentified Veterans (Interview) [tape 2 of 2], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-121)
  - Unidentified Veterans (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-122)
  - Unidentified Veterans (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-123)
  - Unidentified Veterans (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-124)
  - Veltford, Jr., Theodore Ernest (Interview), May 4, 1988 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-125)
  - Voros, Sandor (Interview) [tape 1 of 4], May 20, 1970 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-126)
  - Voros, Sandor (Interview) [tape 2 of 4], May 20, 1970 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-127)
  - Voros, Sandor (Interview) [tape 3 of 4], May 20, 1970 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-128)
  - Voros, Sandor (Interview) [tape 4 of 4], May 20, 1970 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-129)
  - Watson, William (Professor at MIT discussing previously unpublished Hemingway piece on SCW on "All Things Considered," National Public Radio ), Dec 2, 1982 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-130)
  - Weissman, Irving (BROKEN), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-131)
  - Weissman, Irving (Memorial), Feb 20, 1999 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-132)
  - Wolff, Milton (Interview with David Marsamian on KGNU radio), Feb 27, 1985 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-133)
  - Wolff, Milton (Interview with Gonzalo Santo on KGNU radio), Feb 26, 1985 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-134)
  - Wolff, Milton (Interview), May 22, 1970 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-135)
  - Wolff, Milton (Interview), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-136)
  - Wolff, Milton; Carl Frederick Geiser; Pete Randall B. Smith (Interview), 1980 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-137)
- Series II: Public Events, 1970-1999
  - Espana en Ilamas [Spanish], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-140)
  - Poetry by Unidentified Veteran; Mayor of Candeza Speech [Spanish with translator], Aug 2, 1983 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-141)
  - SCW 50th Anniversary in Madrid (Speeches and Music) [Spanish], [1986?] (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-142)
  - Speaker on Spain: Unidentified Male in English, undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-143)
  - Trip to China: Veterans, undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-144)
  - Trip to Nicaragua (Speech and Discussion) [Spanish and English], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-145)
  - Trip to Spain: Meeting [Spanish and English], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-146)
  - Trip to Spain: Speeches, Singing [Spanish and English], (Recorded by Blythe Allison Bennett), Oct 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-147)
  - Trip to Spain: Speeches, Singing [Spanish], (Recorded by Blythe Allison Bennett), Oct 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-148)
  - VALB 46th Anniversary Dinner, (NY Post Tom Wicker and Sister Benedicta), Apr 20, 1983 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-149)
  - VALB 50th Anniversary Celebration (Broken), Aug 7, 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-138)
  - VALB 50th Anniversary; Charles Nusser reading/speaking, [1986?] (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-139)
  - VALB 50th Anniversary Dinner (Bay Area Post, Music and Dramatic Reading), [1986?] (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-150)
  - VALB 50th Anniversary Dinner (Bay Area Post, Music and Dramatic Reading) [tape 1 of 2], Apr 27, 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-151)
  - VALB 50th Anniversary Dinner (Bay Area Post, Music and Dramatic Reading) [tape 2 of 2], Apr 27, 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-152)
  - VALB 50th Anniversary Dinner (NY Post, Music and Dramatic Reading; recording of broadcast by WBAI), [Apr 7, 1986] (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-153)
  - VALB 50th Anniversary Dinner (NY Post, Music and Dramatic Reading; live recording) [tape 1 of 2] [Master], Apr 7, 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-154)
  - VALB 50th Anniversary Dinner (NY Post, Music and Dramatic Reading; live recording) [tape 2 of 2] [Master], Apr 7, 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-155)
  - VALB 50th Anniversary Dinner (NY Post, Music and Dramatic Reading; live recording) [tape 1 of 2] [Copy], Apr 7, 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-156)
  - VALB 50th Anniversary Dinner (NY Post, Music and Dramatic Reading; live recording) [tape 2 of 2] [Copy], Apr 7, 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-157)
  - VALB 50th Anniversary Dinner (NY Post, Music and Dramatic Reading; live recording) [tape 1 of 2] [Copy], Apr 7, 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-158)
  - VALB 50th Anniversary Dinner (NY Post, Music and Dramatic Reading; live recording) [tape 2 of 2] [Copy], Apr 7, 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-159)
  - VALB 55th Anniversary Dinner (NY Post) [Master], Apr 26, 1992 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-160)
  - VALB 55th Anniversary Dinner (NY Post) [Copy], Apr 26, 1992 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-161)
- Series III: Music, 1976-2002.
  - "Espana, Vol. 1" (Commercial Release), 1976 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-162)
  - "Espana Vol. 2" (Commercial Release), 1976 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-163)
  - "La Internacional" (Commercial Release), 1977 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-164)
  - "Last American Heroes," by Harry Fisher's Son (original composition; home recording), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-165)
  - "Ride On," Christy Moore (Commercial Release), 1987 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-166)
  - "Songs of the Spanish Civil War, Vol. #1 and Vol. #2" [tape copy of a Folkways recording], undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-167)
  - "We Had All the Good Songs," by Ross Altman (original composition; home recording), Aug 1987 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-168)
  - [International Brigade Songs] (copy of another recording), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-169)
  - [Six Songs for Democracy Dixos de las Brigadas Internacionales] (tape copy of a record), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-170)
  - [Songs for Democracy] (tape copy of a record), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-171)
  - [Songs of the Lincoln Brigade] and "ILGWU - We Work, We Sing" (tape copy of a record), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-172)
  - [Spanish Civil War Songs] (tape copy of a record), undated (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-173)
  - German and Italian Songs from the SCW (tape copy of a record; made by Tom Sarbaugh), Feb 2002 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-174)
  - Trip to Spain: Singing [Spanish and English] (Recorded by Blythe Allison Bennett), Oct 1986 (Drawer 5, Cassette 1-175)